voteforbernie.org 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy - VoteForBernie.org

## [Privacy Policy](https://voteforbernie.org/privacy/ "Privacy Policy")

_What follows is a bunch of text, but because nobody ever reads those…_

**VoteForBernie’s Privacy Policy, TL;DR:**  
The information you provide will only ever be treated in a way that we would like our own information treated. Privacy is important, and [we need to fight to keep it](http://feelthebern.org/bernie-sanders-on-privacy-and-digital-rights/).

If you have any questions or concerns, please get in contact.

_Now you may read the long-form, if you so desire!_

**Information Collection, Use, and Sharing**

We are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact from you. We will not sell or rent this information to anyone.

We will use your information to respond to you, regarding the reason you contacted us. We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfill your request, e.g. to ship an order.

**Your Access to and Control Over Information**  
You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time, and requests to remove personal data will be fulfilled when possible.

**Cookies**  
We use “cookies” on this site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on a site visitor’s hard drive to help us improve your access to our site and identify repeat visitors to our site. For instance, when we use a cookie to identify you, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information on our site.

  * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to your website.
  * Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/).

**Security**  
We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.

Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for “https” at the beginning of the address of the web page.

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

**Sharing**  
We share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

**Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.

**Updates**

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time and all updates will be posted on this page.

**If you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, you should contact us immediately.**
